

Marco Maida Computer scientist



13 August 1994



github.com/marcomaida



00marcomaida00gmail.com

About me ———

I am a computer scientist currently pursuing a Ph.D. at Max Planck Institute for Software Systems.

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember. In 2013, I started working professionally as a programmer. After three years, I decided to start a bachelor degree in Computer Science, while I kept working part-time as game developer. Once I graduated, I moved to Kaiserslautern, Germany, and started a Joint Master and Ph.D program.

I completed my master courses and just published my first research paper.

Languages ——

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am fluent in English,

und ich spreche etwas Deutsch.

Extras ——

I love camping and traveling with my bike: I often do the two together • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right . Striving not to be the smartest person in the room • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

Skills

I have nine years of professional experience in writing code. I am fluent in writing Python, C#, C++, C, Java, Rust and Coq code. During my seven years in the industry, I learnt to work on big code bases in large and small teams.

Two years in research taught me how study complicated problems and then design, implement, evaluate, document, and finally present my solutions.

I am very **outgoing** and I **love working in teams**. Thanks to my experience in game development, I am used to collaborating with different professional figures (e.g., artists, designers, musicians) and I have an eye for user experience.

Education

since 2019	Ph.D. student Real-time Systems group	Max Planck Institute for Software Systems
since 2019	Master in Computer Science	Technische Universität Kaiserslautern
2016-2019	Bachelor in Computer Science (110/100 cum laude)	Università degli studi di Torino
2015-2016	Game dev: Software Development Private school	t Event Horizon School

Experience

since 2019	Computer Science Researcher.	Max Planck Institute
------------	------------------------------	----------------------

I am currently working on Real-time Systems. My work is focused on timeliness certifications in safety-critical systems using formal verification (Coq) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux.

2016-2019 Game developer.

I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Nintendo Switch, and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, tools and UIs.

2016 Freelance Unity3D developer. Teoresi, Choralia, Maserati

I built an interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D. I shipped on mobile devices and browsers.

2013-2016 Software engineer. R.O. srl

> I worked as a developer using C, C++, C#, and SQL building solutions for glass processing factories. I covered many roles, including traveling to customers to sell, install, and teach our software.

Projects

2021 **Poet - Automatic Proof Generation** Max Planck institute

I developed a tool that computes trustworthy worst-case scenario response times of a system under analysis. Poet automatically produces machine-checked Cog proof scripts as evidence of correctness. An ongoing-work publication has been accepted at RTSS2021, a topclass conference for real-time systems.

2018 Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit. 34BigThings

> I developed a Unity3D framework make the creation of productionready casual games extremely fast, paired by a Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the FMC games. With FMC, I, an artist, and a designer developed ten production-ready games within a month. (www.github.com/340penThings)

Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4.

2017 34BigThings

I developed a framework that handles light effects on Razer's Chroma hardware that are coherent to what is happening in the game. This system is still used today in every 34BigThings game.

(www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)